ZERADAM **FANTAYE**

San Francisco, CA 🏚

(408) 509 - 3646 📞

zeradam.fantaye@gmail.com 💌

LinkedIn profile in

http://zeradamfantaye.com/



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative and highly motivated web developer with technical skills in end-to-end software development and web application design. Possess knowledge of various software languages and tools with fierce passion about user experience and integrate software per requirement. Experienced in object-oriented programming; developing, testing and debugging code; designing interfaces; and administering systems and networks.



EDUCATION

Computer Engineering, BS | University of California, San Diego 09/2013 – 12/2016



EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Intern | Smuggr, Inc 06/2015 – 09/2015

- Collaborated closely with graphic designers to create beautiful, functional, and fast interfaces.
- Constructed a powerful and modern frontend architecture, involving React, Redux, and ES2015; a Node-powered workflow and build system involving gulp, webpack, PostCSS, and other tools; a systematic, scalable, and auto-enforced CSS methodology; keyboardfriendly and fully accessible interfaces; and complex configuration and theming capabilities, allowing for deep customization.
- Built large-scale web applications and mobile-first websites using JavaScript, and React.
- Collaborate with the application architect and backend developers on JSON API design.
- Created and implemented a custom CSS grid system, with CSS media queries for mobile responsiveness.
- Created and maintained the front-end standards document and oversaw production of JavaScript, HTML, and CSS (and PHP for the WordPress blog).
- Programmed HTML5 canvases to animate particles on web backgrounds for site-wide promotions.
- Developed fully functional responsive prototypes based on Business Requirements using HTML/HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery.

Research Assistant, Intern | University of California, San Diego 01/2014 – 04/2014

- Researched industry trends and websites to provide top quality design
- Converted Photoshop layouts to web pages using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Provided internet related services including web site design, front-end web development, domain name registration, web hosting, search engine optimization / submission.
- Fixed front-end bugs (HTML, CSS, JavaScript errors (JQUERY), testing (A/B Split Testing), unit testing.
- Analyzed traffic and made necessary changes for a better user experience
- Developed code for Shadowboxes, Slider Carousals, Tickers, Rotating Headers, Validation and JS animations.
- Executed and contributed to full-stack web development projects, with an emphasis on front end features, browser manipulation, and cross-browser compatibility.



TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Front-End Development: HTML5, CSS, CSS3, jQuery, ReactJS, Redux, Ajax, JavaScript, bootstrap, Semantic UI, UIKit, Sass and LESS
- Back-End Development: PHP, NodeJS, Express, mongoose, MongoDB, SQL server
- High-Level Language: C, C++, Java
- Version Control: GIT, Github
- Operating Systems: UNIX, Windows, iOS
- Design Patter: MVC, RESTful API, LAMP stack